Everybody likes to get a freebie - something given to you to try for free.
每个人都喜欢得到免费赠品——也就是免费给你试用的东西。
On my commute to work today I was offered a complimentary sample of washing powder and a bottle of new mineral water.
今天在我通勤上班的路上，有人给了我一份免费赠送的洗衣粉样品和一瓶新的矿泉水。
Lucky me eh?
我很幸运，对吧？
Well it's not necessarily down to luck - where you can grab a freebie depends on a number of factors.
嗯，这不一定全靠运气——你在哪里能拿到免费赠品取决于很多因素。
For businesses, giving out something for nothing is an important marketing technique.
对于企业来说，免费赠送东西是一种重要的营销手段。
We might not give it much thought but they are keen to see our reaction and hear our feedback and ultimately make us buy more.
我们可能不会过多地去想这件事，但企业很想看到我们的反应，听到我们的反馈，最终让我们购买更多的产品。
But who they hear from is very crucial.
但是，他们听取谁的意见是非常关键的。
They want to target the so-called trendsetters and influencers, in the hope that they will speak positively about the product and then sell more.
他们想要以所谓的潮流引领者和有影响力的人为目标群体，希望这些人会对产品给予积极评价，然后促进更多的销售。
In the UK, one upmarket popcorn brand gave away free bags at London Fashion Week in order for fashionistas to create a buzz about their product.
在英国，一个高档爆米花品牌的制造商在伦敦时装周上赠送免费的爆米花袋，以便让时尚人士为他们的产品制造话题。
A spokesman said: “It‘s less about an immediate sales lift and more about getting our product into the hands of those who will be excited to engage with our brand and story firsthand.”
一位发言人说：“这与其说是为了立即提高销售额，不如说是为了让那些会兴奋地亲身参与到我们品牌和故事的人拿到我们的产品。”
Living in a capital city certainly improves your chances of getting a freebie.
住在首都城市肯定会增加你获得免费赠品的机会。
Not only is the population larger but these places are often considered the trendsetter for retail purchases.
不仅是因为那里人口更多，而且这些地方通常被认为是零售购物的潮流引领者。
So if you live in London, Paris or Beijing you‘ll probably see a new promotional campaign launched there first.
所以，如果你住在伦敦、巴黎或北京，你可能会首先看到在那里发起的新的促销活动。
The hope is that the fashionable city dwellers will try and like the new item and endorse it on social media.
人们希望时尚的城市居民会试用并喜欢上新产品，并在社交媒体上推荐它。
Eventually everyone around the country will know about it.
最终，全国的每个人都会知道这个产品。
How businesses give away freebies is also of interest.
企业如何发放免费赠品也很有意思。
According to behavioural economist Enrico Trevisan, they have three different approaches: “future selling, cross-selling and up-selling”.
根据行为经济学家恩里科·特雷维桑的说法，他们有三种不同的方式：“未来销售、交叉销售和追加销售”。
The first is about giving something away assuming we will like it and buy more later.
第一种方式是在假设我们会喜欢赠品并且以后会购买更多产品的情况下赠送东西。
“With cross-selling, the company tries to gain new clients through an entrance product, with the intention of selling them additional products during their life cycle” and ’up-selling‘ happens when a basic version is given away for free but charges a client for more advanced and complete versions.
“在交叉销售中，公司试图通过一种入门产品来获得新客户，并打算在之后向他们销售更多其他产品”，而“追加销售”则是指免费赠送一个基本版本，但向客户收取更高级和完整版本的费用时发生的情况。
Maybe you‘ve experienced one of these approaches?
也许你曾经历过这些方式中的一种？
Of course a freebie is not actually free — someone has to pay for it and this usually comes from a firm‘s marketing budget which is funded by the products we buy — so the expression ’there‘s no such thing as a free lunch’ could be true!
当然，免费赠品实际上并不是免费的——总得有人为此买单，而这笔费用通常来自公司的营销预算，而营销预算又是由我们购买的产品来支付的——所以“天下没有免费的午餐”这句话可能是对的！